# Vilma Recchiuti

Graphic Designer

22 Stonard Road, N134DP, London www.vilmare.com email: vilmare@hotmail.com

mobile: 07574546831



#### BUSINESS PROFILE

Creative, accurate, independent and reliable.
Passion for finding solutions using technical abilities and creative resourses.

My work experience ranges from freelance to corporate business and start up companies in fields such as Finance, e-commerce, travel, art and social network. I feel comfortable working alone and in teams.

I am always keen to learn new approaches to technology tools and processes.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2004 to Present Freelance Graphic Designer
Photo retouching, brochures,
logos, rollups,
website graphic elements,
html and css for pages layout.

musicians Duo Romanelli Allevi, Italy Photocert, London artist Naomi Tagini, Italy, USA Inevo, Italy Made in Italy Mall (e-commerce), Ca, USA El remedio natural (e-commerce), Ca, USA

2007 to 2012 Graphic Designer
Graphic elements
(Illustrator, Photoshop and
Dreamweaver),
a tool to build avatars (Flash),
SEO for the pages.

Ioken (social network), California

Oct 2008 April 2009 Internship

I collaborated in projects about issues of interest in the local community: using video camera for in studio interviews, in the making of a video about the risk of driving under the effect of alchool and other tasks.

Public Cable Television Authority Huntington Beach, California Aug 2002

Web Designer

Aug 2003

At www.venere.com, an European Travel Accommodation Search Engine, I used to find the right solution gathering the hotel managers requisites, considering the users needs and the portal resourses; as a result I built different but personalized websites, each for every luxury hotel, villas, resorts, apartment all contained in the portal structure with its own criteria. Tools used Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Html, Venere Net SpA (now Expedia) Roma, Italy

Jun 1999

Web Designer

Pf Network, a Financial planner portal and Dec 2001 search engine, a startup company and

an experiment for that time.

A real gym for creativity and professional

experience.

Tools used: Dreamweaver, Flash, Photoshop and free hand drafts and drawings.

Pf Network S.r.l. Alba Adriatica, Italy

April 1994

Internship Sept 1994

Collaboration in a specific research project about the impact of micro pollution on monuments.

University of L'Aquila, Department of Microbiology L'Aquila, Italy

Oct 1993

Internship

I was part of the Microbiological Quality Mar 1994 Control Team, testing all the pharmaceutical

products before they got out the production

lines into the market.

Hoechst Pharmaceutical L'Aquila, Italy

**EDUCATION** 

2009

Certificate in

Digital Media Arts and Design,

Multimedia

(program of 4 semesters plus

internship)

Orange Coast College, Costa Mesa, California, USA

1993

Bachelor of Science in

Biology

(program of 4 years plus 2 on original research thesis)

L'Aquila University, Italy

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

2017 2017 2016	(UX) User Experience Gestalt Psychology and Web Design Bootstrap	IDF (Interaction Design Foundation) online IDF online online
2009	(SEO) Search engine optimization	online
2008 2008 2008 2007 2007 2006 2006 2006 2005 2005	History of Graphic Design Digital film and video editing 3-D Computer Graphics Animation Painting Webpage design Dreamweaver Digital Photography Illustrator Color and Design: two-dimensional Art Photography Drawing Photoshop	OCC (Orange Coast Collage) California OCC California
2001 1998	Css Html	
1994	Professional qualification as a Biologi	st University of L'Aquila, Italy

### LANGUAGES

Italian English